つまり福ちゃんは こう言いたいわけね
型に入れて冷やして固めただけのチョコは手作りじゃないと
だから受け取らないと
そう言いたいのね
まあ 平たく言えばね
そう 分かったわよ
福ちゃんがその気なら
覚えてなさい
来年福ちゃんが満足するような傑作を
その横面に叩き付けてやるんだから
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
KamiGami
複雑に構えた今日が 息を呑んで澄ましてる
身に覚えあるだろう 君はどうしたい
何もなかったそぶりで  かばう痛みはもう
心強いくらいに 急かすんだ
掴んでこぼして 不完全な僕たちが
光って見えない 未来の自分を創れるなら
This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
So you're telling me...
目覚めるまま走れ 蜃気楼を追い越して
that the chocolate I just poured into a mold and let cool doesn't count as handmade,
変わりたいまま走れ 自由な違和感で
so you won't accept it?
That's what you're saying?!
Well... yeah, pretty much.
届きそうな輝きと今を選んでいこう
I see...
I get it!
If that's what you want...
飛びたつ手を知らない
Remember this!
深い 浅い 呼吸を重ねて
Next year, I'm gonna make one that even you'll like
and smash it into your stupid cheeks!
Kaburaya Junior High School
The Chocolate Files
Making chocolate from cocoa beans is just impossible!
やっぱりカカオ豆からチョコを作るなんて無理じゃない
手制巧克力事件
そうみたいですね
It would seem so...
But I'm not giving up.
でも 諦めないわ
I'm gonna make the best chocolate ever with my own two hands!
最高の手作りチョコを作ればいいのよ
And if Fuku's still not happy,
それでも福ちゃんがうだうだ言ったら
I'll clap him in irons and read him this book from cover to cover!
どこかに監禁して
この本をじっくり読み聞かせるわ
And if even that's not enough, I'll hammer the chocolate into his mouth!
それでも駄目なら
口にチョコを押し込んでやる
Mayaka, I'm rooting for you!
摩耶花さん
応援してます
ええ
Uh-oh...
おいおい
If there's any way I can help, just let me know!
何か手伝えることがあったら言ってください
Oh right, Chi!
そうだ チーちゃん
Do you know any candy stores or places where they sell the ingredients?
洋菓子店とかが使う材料を売ってるとこ知らない
Now that you mention it...
そうですね 市場の傍にプロ向けの食材を扱うお店がありました
I remember there was an ingredient shop for professionals near the marketplace.
Would you like me to show you?
案内しましょうか
You would?
本当
Sure.
はい
Hooray!
やったー
Can you keep this...
このこと福ちゃんには
...a secret from Fukube?
内緒ですね
では 今週の日曜日はいかがですか
Then I'll show you where it is on Sunday.
Aren't you forgetting someone here?
存在 忘れられてないか
オーケー 案内して
Okay. Thanks.
Oh, Oreki.
折木
Yeah?
Don't you tell him either, okay?
あんたも言わないでね
Sure...
ああ
On pain of death.
絶対よ
I won't.
言いませんとも
I really wish you wouldn't glare at me like that.
その目はやめていただけるとありがたい
That's Satoshi's.
里志のだな
や 奉太郎
Hey, Houtarou!
You showed up at just the right time.
ちょうどいいところに通りかかったね
How about a battle for old times' sake?
どう 久しぶりに一勝負
Well, I don't need to be home in a hurry.
急いで帰る理由もないか
This reminds me of junior high.
中学以来だな
僕もさ
Yeah, me too.
I'll take the Viper 2.
バイバーツーで行くよ
You're using Raiden, right?
奉太郎は雷電だろ
It's the only one I know.
これしか使えん
I thought he'd keep running away.
てっきり逃げに徹するかと思ったんだが
Is this how he always fought?
里志はこんな戦い方だったか
No, it's definitely different.
いや 明らかに違う
During junior high, he only focused on winning the game.
中学時代の里志のプレイは
勝つことだけが目的だった
He wasn't picky about the way he played as long as it meant he'd win.
勝つためなら手段を選ばなかった
If he lost, he didn't even try to hide his frustration.
もし自分が負けると 隠さず悔しがり
That wasn't fair!
ちゃんと動けよ
He was a really sore loser.
負け惜しみが強かった
Switch sides and let's go again!
場所交替してもう一回
Is he gonna dash above me?
引っ掛けるつもりか
いやー いい勝負だったね
Good game, man.
I like how vigorously you pull on the joystick, Houtarou.
あの鮮やかなスティック捌き
見事だよ 奉太郎
なあ さっきの最後 何で無理に突っ込んできた
Hey,
about that game...
Why did you rush at me like that at the end?
In a battle between giant robots, close combat's the really exciting part.
ロボットものなら 白刃戦はロマン
Don't you agree?
だと思わないかい
This is how he is now.
そう
これが今の里志だ
He's changed a lot from junior high.
中学の頃と変わったな
Jeez!
もう
Why am I so nervous already?!
今から緊張してどうすんだろ
He'll be only too happy to accept it, I'm sure.
きっと受け取ってくれますよ
That'd be nice...
だといいんだけど
By the way, Chi...
ところで チーちゃんってさ
好きな人いないの
Do you have a guy you like?
Uh, I...
その 私は
痒い
Itchy...
Here, a block of chocolate to remember me by.
板チョコ一枚お土産です
From Oreki Tomoe, with heartfelt...
折木供恵より震える「哀」をこめて
Condolences
condolences.
Oreki, good morning!
折木さん おはようございます
Morning.
おはよう
How did Ibara's chocolate turn out?
そう言えば 伊原のチョコはどうなった
できました
It's done!
But it wasn't easy.
でもなかなか大変だったんです
We had to sample lots of other chocolate to get it right.
いろんなチョコを試食して
どうせあっという間に食い尽したんだろ
I bet you sampled as much as you could, huh?
You're mean, Oreki.
ひどいです 折木さん
Sorry.
悪い
でもそのお陰で傑作が完成しましたよ
Anyway, after all that we were able to complete it.
So that's what it means to put your heart into something.
心を込めるってああいうことなんでしょうか
素敵ですね
Isn't it wonderful?
So what's the plan, then?
それで チョコはどうするんだ
Mayaka can't get out of going to the Manga Lab,
それが 摩耶花さん どうしても漫画研究会が抜けられないらしくて
so she'll probably just leave it in the clubroom for him.
ですから 部室に置いておくとか
It's a shame.
残念です
里志が喜びそうな演出だと思うがな
Satoshi will be happy with that.
Oh...
Oreki...
折木さん
その 今日が
Um... Today is Valentine's Day, right?
バレンタインですが
My family has this rule against giving presents to people close to us during the year.
私の家では 本当に親しい方にはお歳暮やお中元を
お送りしないことにしてるんです
So...
ですので バレンタインも
Even on Valentine's Day...
What's that...
それって
Um...
あの
supposed to...
つまり
どうなの
mean?
They say it's gonna snow today.
今日雪降るって
What, seriously?
嘘 マジで
And I forgot my umbrella, too...
傘忘れた
We'll be late!
遅刻しちゃいますね
Y-Yeah.
Let's go!
行きましょうか
O-Okay...
Earth Sci. Prep. Room
To Fuku
Please accept this
Valentine's Day chocolate.
Mayaka
Houtarou, are you going to the clubroom?
奉太郎
これから部室に行くのかい
No, I'll wait in the library and see if this sleet stops or turns to snow.
いや 霙が止むか雪になるまで図書室で待つ
The clubroom's so cold.
部室は寒いからな
You're going there?
お前は部室か
Yeah.
ああ そうだよ
Ibara can't go because she has to be at the Manga Lab.
伊原 漫研で来られんそうだな
News travels fast, I see.
耳が早いね
千反田さんか
You heard from Chitanda?
See you later.
じゃ僕はここで
Satoshi.
里志
Good luck.
頑張れよ
With what? Jeez.
何をだよ まったく
Earth Sci. Prep. room
Library
折木さん
Oreki!
Ah, Chitanda.
おー 千反田
福部さんを知りませんか
Do you know where Fukube is?
He didn't turn up?
来てないのか
Nope. What if something happened to him?
はい ひょっとして何かあったのかと
I saw him about half an hour ago.
30分くらい前に会ったが
He said he was going to the clubroom.
部室に行くとは言ってたぞ
Okay. Then I'll wait a little longer.
分かりました もう少し待ってみます
福部さん 遅いです
Fukube... you're late.
Oreki!
折木さん 待ってください
Wait!
This is terrible!
大変なんです
The sleet finally stopped, so I'm going home.
やっと霙が止んで今から帰るところなんだ
It can wait until tomorrow.
悪いが 明日にしてくれ
おい
Hey...
ごめんなさい でも話だけでも聞いてください
I'm sorry.
But please, at least hear me out.
It's my fault for carelessly leaving the room unlocked.
私がいけなかったんです
うかつに部屋を空けるから
摩耶花さんに 申し訳なく
What am I going to say to Mayaka?
Satoshi,
里志
what happened?
何があった
Well...
いや それが
チョコが 摩耶花さんのチョコが
The chocolate...
The chocolate that Mayaka made...
was stolen!
盗まれたんです
はあ
I get it. I'll help.
分かった 手伝ってやる
Thanks.
はい
I don't want to see what happens if Ibara finds out her chocolate was stolen.
俺もチョコを盗まれたと知った伊原は見たくないからな
I'm not a fan of horror stories.
何しろ 俺はホラーが苦手なんだ
History of the Hanya mask
立春
春意伊始是也
Beginning of Spring
As the winds of spring rise...
Hyouka
Oh, Oreki,
あっ 折木さん
Freshly waxed.
No entry.
we can't use the west stairway to reach the fourth floor.
四階への西階段 今使えないみたいなんです
Let's take the east.
東階段から行こう
Sorry, do you have a moment?
わっ ちょっとごめん
Does this look straight to you?
これ 水平かな
Not at all.
歪だな
It looks trapezoidal.
台形
You lowered it too much.
下げ過ぎだね
Huh? Well...
Oh, crap.
何てこった
It was here.
ここに置いてあったんです
It was in a transparent plastic bag.
透明なビニールのラッピングで
About this big, shaped like a heart.
大きさはこれぐらいのハート型です
Quite big.
でかいな
It was here when I went to look for Fukube.
福部さんを探しに行くまではここにあったんです
When did you return to the clubroom?
お前が部室に戻ってきたのは
Past five.
5時過ぎでした
15分ほどの間 鍵をかける手間を惜しんだばっかりに
I didn't want to lock the door for just fifteen minutes...
You shouldn't blame yourself, Chitanda.
千反田さんがそんなに気に病むことはないよ
It's my fault for being so late.
遅くなった僕の方がずっと悪い
Does Ibara know?
このことを伊原には
No.
言ってません 卑怯かもしれませんが
It might not be the nicest thing, but I'd prefer to look for it first.
できるだけ探してからにするつもりです
この部屋にはなかったんだな
It's not in this room?
はい 部室と校舎周りを私と福部さんで探しました
No. Fukube and I checked this room and looked around the building.
Satoshi too?
里志も
そこの階段で会ったから
We met by the stairs, so we came to the clubroom together.
二人で部室に来たんだ
I see.
なるほどな
How long was that Artisan guy there?
そう言えば あの工作員いつからいた
Artisan guy?
工作員
That guy with the glasses.
あの眼鏡の奴だ
Oh, the Artisan Workshop member.
工作部の方ですね
When I went to look for Fukube,
確か福部さんを探しに行く時にポスターを広げてましたが
I'm sure he was already working on that poster.
Great.
好都合だ
工作員があそこにずっといたなら
If he was there, he might remember who came and went.
行き来した奴を覚えてるかもしれない
I see!
なるほど
Wait.
待って
What if he was the culprit?
あいつが犯人の可能性は
Not a chance.
あり得ない
Who would just hang around putting up a poster after committing theft?
盗みの後に呑気にポスターを張る犯人がいるわけないだろ
True that.
違いないや
You're asking if I saw anyone pass by?
ここを通った奴
Yes.
はい
Sure.
覚えてるよ
I remember all three of them.
全部で三人
三人
Three...
Who were they?
ど どんな方でした
ええ
Do you remember any character—
何か特徴がありませんでした
一人
One.
Two.
二人
Three.
三人
うん
So the culprit is still on the fourth floor.
つまり犯人はまだ四階にいるってことか
Satoshi, what clubs meet on the fourth floor?
里志 ここの四階に入ってる部活は
The Classics Club, the Light Music Club, the Astrology Club and the Philosophy Circle.
確か 古典部 軽音部 天文部 思想研かな
But I think only we and the Astrology people are still here.
けどまだ帰ってないのは僕たちと天文部だけだと思うよ
By the way, I'm surprised to see
にしても珍しいね
that you're actually trying.
奉太郎がやる気なんてさ
What if the sleet comes back?
また霙でも降るんじゃないかい
Cut it out.
ほっとけ
Now we can get it back.
これで取り戻せますね
But why would anyone do this?
でも 何のためにこんなことを
That's the problem.
問題はそこだな
First of all, let's consider the possibilities.
ここはひとまず可能性を探してみよう
General Use Room #5
Coming!
はーい
Huh? The Classics Club?
古典部
Give back our chocolate!
チョコレートを返してください
Sorry, we just wanted to ask you something.
先輩にちょっとお聞きしたいことがありまして
ふーん 何
What?
Um...
えっと
実は部室からバレンタインチョコが盗まれたんですが
A box of Valentine's Day chocolate was taken from our clubroom.
We're looking for anyone who might know what happened.
その目撃者を捜しています
Chocolate?
チョコ
恋泥棒じゃあるまいし
Why would we even...
Did you see anyone pass by here between a quarter to five and five?
4時45分から5時くらいまでの間 誰か見ませんでしたか
Well, the discussion was getting kinda lively.
私ら結構盛り上がったからね
I don't remember exactly when,
時間は覚えてないけど
but only Nakayama and Yoshiwara left the room.
席を外したのは中山と吉原 小田も出たかな
Oh, and Oda too, maybe.
五人中三人か
Three out of five?
Has anyone gone home?
帰り支度で出た人はいますか
No.
いなかったけど
Is Oda that girl?
小田さんってあの女の人ですか
それは中山
She's Nakayama.
言っとくけど 探偵君
Lemme make this clear, detective boy.
None of 'em brought any chocolate back here.
誰もチョコを持ってきた奴なんていなかったわよ
Hey guys, any of you seen any chocolate around?
あんたたち ここにいる間にチョコっぽいもの
ちらりとでも見た
Man, you just gotta rub salt into the wound, don't you?
先輩 あんま悲しいこと言わないでもらえますか
I wish...
見たって言いてー
No chance.
縁なさそう
だってさ 聞きたいことはそれだけ
You heard 'em.
Is that all?
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました 先輩
失礼なことを言って すみません
Sorry to have bothered you.
Well, whatever.
まあ いいけどね
Where were we again?
はい 再開再開
遅いっすよ 先輩
Sawakiguchi got angry...
沢木口さん 怒ってましたね
Of course.
当然だろう
But we have to get Mayaka's chocolate back!
でも 摩耶花さんのチョコだけは取り戻さないと
Houtarou.
奉太郎
Let's just return to the classroom for now.
とにかくいったん教室へ戻ろう
そろそろけりもつけたいしな
I should put an end to this.
あの階段以外に四階にあがる手段はあるか
Is there any way to reach the fourth floor other than the east stairs?
現実的に考えて ワックスが塗られた方の階段かな
Realistically speaking, only the freshly waxed west stairs.
But there was no sign anyone had used them.
けど 使った跡はなかったよ
I see.
そうか
By the way, have you checked the girls' restroom?
そういえば 女子トイレは探したのか
I'll go look!
見てきます
Do you really think it'd be in the restroom?
本当にトイレにあると思うかい
It might as well be.
万にひとつもないだろうな
Might as well?
万にひとつって…
Satoshi!
里志
I've pretty much figured it out.
大体の目星はついてる
少し黙ってろ
Shut up.
I see.
そうか
It wasn't there.
ありませんでした
Then there's only one place it could be.
なら 可能性はひとつだ
Huh?
あれ
Why are you all here?
なんでみんな揃ってるの？
Um... Mayaka—
あの 摩耶花さん…
So?
でさ どうだった？
How was it?
私のチョコ
The chocolate I made.
いきなりくるか
Straight to the point.
Ibara—
伊原…
I'm sorry, Mayaka!
ごめんなさい 摩耶花さん
I left the classroom unlocked, and the chocolate was stolen.
私が戸締りをせずに教室を出た間に
チョコが盗まれてしまいました
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい
I see...
そっか
It was stolen...
盗まれちゃったか
Mayaka, I...
摩耶花さん 私…
Don't make that face. It's nothing you should apologize for.
そんな顔しないで
ちーちゃんが謝るようなことなんて何もないよ
But it's hard.
でも ちょっときついかな
I'm going home.
今日は帰るね
Don't worry about it, Chi!
ちーちゃん 本当に気にしないでね
Step aside.
退いてください
What do you want to do?
どうする気だ
多少強引な方法使ってでも チョコを探します
I'll find the chocolate, even if I have to use force.
Otherwise, how could I face Mayaka tomorrow?
そうしないと
明日から摩耶花さんに合わせる顔がありません
It's not your fault.
お前のせいじゃない
I can't forgive myself!
私が 私を許せないんです
摩耶花さんは 今日嬉しい思いをするはずだったのに
Mayaka should've been happy today!
I can't say I understand how you feel.
その気持ち 分かるとは言えない
I'm nowhere near as emotional as you are.
俺はお前ほど感じやすくないからな
But please leave this to me. I've got an idea.
だが ここは俺に任せてくれ
考えてることがある
I can't do it with you around, though.
でも それはお前がいるとできない
心当たりは？
You have an idea?
Yeah.
ああ
It was Nakayama from the Astrology Club.
天文部の中山だ
Ibara's chocolate was quite big.
伊原のチョコは結構な大きさなんだよな
You wouldn't be able to hide it under a guy's uniform.
なら 学生服では隠せない
Even if you did, you couldn't move naturally.
内側に隠しても動きが不自然になる
But a girl's uniform is different.
だが セーラー服ならできる
If you tie it to your leg, the skirt will hide it.
足に括りつければスカートが隠してくれる
I'll deliver Ibara's chocolate to Satoshi today.
伊原のチョコは今日中に 俺が里志に渡す
ここは俺に預けて お前は安心して帰ってくれ
Leave this to me. Calm down and go home.
Okay.
わかりました
I'll believe in you.
折木さんを信じます
Shall we get going?
帰るか
Yeah.
そうだね
Satoshi, give me your bag.
里志 その巾着を貸せ
I'm giving you Ibara's chocolate.
伊原のチョコ お前に渡す
Now I've fulfilled the promise I made to Chitanda.
これで千反田との約束は果たした
You were the one who stole Ibara's chocolate.
伊原のチョコを盗んだのは
里志だ
Nice job, Houtarou.
見事だ 奉太郎
When I heard the chocolate was stolen,
チョコが盗まれたと聞いた時点で
I thought you were the only one who'd do something like that.
そんなことをするやつは里志しかいないと考えていた
After I talked to the Artisan guy, that confirmed it.
確信したのは工作員に声をかけられたとき
You said he'd lowered the poster too much.
里志は「下げすぎたね」と言った
You wouldn't have said that unless you'd told him to lower the right side of it before.
事前に「右を下げた方がいい」と言ってなければ
そんな返答はしないだろう
おそらく 里志は三階男子トイレに隠れて 千反田をやりすごし
You probably waited in the guys' restroom on the third floor until Chitanda passed,
Earth Sci. Prep. Room
then took the chocolate from the empty clubroom.
無人の部室でチョコを回収する
Earth Sci. Prep. Room
But it was too big,
だが それは意外に大きかった
so you couldn't put it in your bag, nor was there another bag big enough in the clubroom.
巾着には入らないし
部室内に適当な大きさの袋もない
You couldn't risk running into Chitanda while escaping with it in your hand.
そのまま持って逃げて 万一千反田と出くわせばアウト
So in the end, you...
となれば 里志のとった行動は
You didn't hesitate for one moment before breaking it into pieces?
そいつを砕くとき 迷わなかったのか
Now we're even.
これで借りは返した
借り？
Even?
Last April, you helped me escape Chitanda using that Golden Web story.
去年の四月
女郎蜘蛛の会の件で 千反田から逃げるのに話を作った
Oh, that's right.
ああ あったね そんなことも
But no one got hurt there.
でも あれは誰も傷つかなかった
Except for you.
奉太郎以外はね
Could you at least explain yourself?
説明ぐらいはしてもらえるんだろうな
If you say it was just a joke...
もし冗談だったなんて言ったら
What if I do?
言ったら？
I'll have no choice but to punch you.
殴るしかないだろうな
For Chitanda and Ibara as well.
千反田と伊原の分 グーで
I'd rather not get punched.
殴られるのは嫌だな
I don't wanna say it, but I guess I've got no choice.
言いたくない
けど 言わないと駄目なんだろうな
Do you think I'm the dedicated type?
奉太郎は僕をこだわり派の人間だと思うかい
You're more of a hobbyist.
趣味人だとは思う
That's where you're wrong.
そこが誤解だよ
People like that immerse themselves in a particular field,
そういう人はね 何かに打ち込んでその分野では誰にも負けたくないって思うんだ
and in that field they don't want to lose to anyone.
Are you different, then?
お前は違うのか
I am. I can never be the best.
違うね
僕は第一人者にはなれない
But to be honest, I've already stopped trying.
だけど 正確に言うなら 僕は…
なろうとするのをやめたんだ
You felt something was off at the arcade too, right?
ゲームセンターで奉太郎も違和感覚えたみたいじゃないか
I wasn't going on about losing.
僕が勝ちにこだわらなかったことに
ああ
Yeah.
I used to dedicate myself to a bunch of things for the sake of winning.
昔の僕は勝つために勝ちたがって いろんなことにこだわった
I was a real bore, wasn't I?
つまらなかったね
I wanted to win so much, but even if I did,
それだけ勝ちたがって勝っても
つまらないんだから 始末に終えないだろ
it was a boring, nasty way to win.
It's not fun unless you have fun winning.
面白い勝ち方をしなきゃ 面白いもんか
One day I realized that.
で ある日僕はそれにあきた
I dedicated myself to not dedicating myself to anything.
「こだわらない」ことにこだわるようになったんだ
I've had lots of fun since then.
それからはね 本当に楽しいんだ
I'm happy every day!
毎日がハッピーさ
But there was one problem left:
でも 一つだけ問題があった
Mayaka.
摩耶花だ
She's really nice. In a class of her own.
摩耶花はいいよ 本当にいい
あんな子ほかにいない
It's like a dream that she wants to be with me.
その摩耶花が僕に一緒にいてほしいだなんて
夢みたいな話さ
Then...
なら…
But...
だけどだよ
Should I dedicate myself to her?
僕は摩耶花にこだわってもいいのかな
I want to be with her, that much is for sure.
僕は間違いなく摩耶花と一緒にいたい
But I don't want to dedicate myself.
でも こだわりたくないんだ
It's all just for my own convenience.
全部僕のわがままだよ
I haven't even considered her feelings.
摩耶花の気持ちなんて考えてない
Don't you think I'm a bit too selfish?
あまりにも自己中だと思わないかい
Even though I don't want to neglect her.
摩耶花をないがしろにはしたくないのに
But if I let go of my easy-going style and accepted Mayaka,
それに今の気楽さを手放して 摩耶花を受け入れてしまったら
I'd end up turning back into my old self.
昔の自分に戻ってしまうかもしれない
To be honest, that's what I'm scared of.
それを怖いと思ってしまうんだ
That's why you won't accept her?
だから受け取らなかったのか
Yeah.
そうとも そして今年だ
Last year, and this year too.
But I still don't have an answer.
なのに僕はまだ答えが出てないんだ
This was the only way not to accept a chocolate I couldn't accept.
受け取れないチョコを受け取らない方法はこれしかなかった
But you hurt Chitanda!
だがお前は千反田を傷つけた
奉太郎みたいにうまくはいかないね
These things don't go as well for me as they do for you.
Chitanda was the mistake in this equation between Mayaka and I.
僕と摩耶花の誤算は千反田さんだった
Mayaka! Wait!
摩耶花さん 待ってください
Chi?
ちーちゃん
Um—
あの…
I'm sorry, Chi!
ごめん ちーちゃん
I know who stole the chocolate.
あたし チョコ盗んだの誰か分かってるの
Last Valentine's Day I told Fuku that I'd wait for his answer.
実は去年のバレンタインのあと
福ちゃんの答えが出るまで待つって言ったの
Today was the anniversary of that day.
今日がその試験日だったんだ
Then the chocolate...
じゃあ チョコは…
He probably has it, yeah.
多分福ちゃんが持ってると思う
I... see.
そう だったんですか
It feels like I've deceived you. I'm sorry.
結果的にちーちゃんを騙したみたいになって
本当にごめんなさい
It's okay... I'm the one who let things escalate.
いいんです
私の方こそ 騒ぎを大きくしてしまったみたいで
Then, when Oreki said that he thought one of the Astrology Club members had stolen it...
じゃあ 折木さんが「天文部の方が盗んだ」と言っていたのも…
I think he was covering for Fuku.
福ちゃんを庇って嘘ついたんだと思う
そうですか
I see.
But how could Fukube just act as if it got stolen?
でも ひどいです 福部さん
盗まれたことにするなんて
I know, right?
やっぱそう思う
Yeah!
そうですよ
ほんっとむかつく
It pisses me off so bad!
But the fact that I still love him pisses me off even more!
でもそんな福ちゃんをまだ好きな自分が一番むかつく
よし ちーちゃん 今からケーキ食べにいこう
Chi, let's go and eat a cake somewhere!
Okay.
はい
And that's the whole story, Houtarou.
さあ 奉太郎 僕の話はこれで全部だ
どうする
What you gonna do?
We can't tell Chitanda this.
今の話 千反田にはできないな
I know. I'd rather get punched.
無理だね 殴られたほうがましだよ
Do you know how you're gonna answer?
それで 答えられる目処は立ってるのか
状況は非科学的に 感情のモンタージュ
I just need a little more time.
もう少しで答えがでそうなんだ
そうか
I see.
誰が誰を呼んでる
振り向けば逃げてく視線（感じる）
You're pretty stupid for someone so smart.
お前は器用なくせに 不器用すぎる
気のせいじゃつれないよ アンテナは才能って言うでしょ
Guess I should tell him, "I'm sorry. I didn't know anything about you."
「すまん お前のことを何も分かってなかった」
と言うべきなんだろうが
No way I could.
まあ 言えないな
だって（だって） 知りたい（君は違うの？）
Yeah, I delivered the chocolate to Satoshi.
ああ 無事里志にチョコを渡したからな
青春の温度差 今のうち正してあげるよ
I see. I'm glad to hear it.
そうですか 安心しました
Don't worry too much about all this.
まあ あまり気にするな
明日解決するなら 今でもよくない？
Oreki,
折木さん 今日は色々ありがとうございました
thank you for everything you did today.
君のミステリー解いてみたい
Sure.
ああ
少年の秘密めいた背中探せ（今日も）
Mayaka
Call
Write message
FaceTime
Send contact details
Add to most used
君はファンタジー 惹かれてゆくよ（ずるい）
Hello. Um...
もしもし あのさ
膨らんだ好奇心 とりたくはないのに
話があるんだ
We've gotta talk.
気になるよ 興味深い どうして
Not bad.
苦い
The situation is unscientific
A montage of emotions
Who's calling who?
You look away when our eyes are about to meet
I can feel it
Am I just imagining things? It's so cold of you
It takes talent to read minds
You know
I wanna know
Don't you?
I'll fix the fire of youth in your heart while I can
If we can do it today why leave it for tomorrow
I want to solve your mystery
Look for the back of the boy, burdened with secrets
Even today
You are a fantasy and I'm drawn to you
This growing curiosity
There's no twist in the story
I can't stop thinking about it
It's so interesting
But why?
Next time: Doll in the Distance.
次回 遠回りする雛
Doll in the Distance